Register of the James B. Donovan papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Abel-Powers Spy Exchange File, 1957-1964 (Boxes 20-33)
  - Correspondence
    - Van Orman, Francis, 1957 (Folder 4)
    - Veschunov, S., 1958 (Folder 5)
    - Vogel, Wolfgang, 1958-1962 (Folder 6)
    - Wallace, Edward B., 1957 (Folder 7)
    - Walsh, James D., 1957 (Folder 8)
    - Waterman, Sterry R., 1958 (Folder 9)
    - Waters and Donovan, 1962 (Folder 10)
    - Webb, Neeta, 1962 (Folder 11)
    - Wiegel, H. B., 1962 (Folder 12)
    - Weissberg, Joseph, 1962 (Folder 13)
    - White, Ronnie, 1962 (Folder 14)
    - White, W. L., 1962 (Folder 15)
    - Wickersham, Cornelius W., 1957-1960 (Folder 16)
    - Wilkins, Roy, 1964 (Folder 17)
    - Wilkinson, Frederick T., 1959-1962 (Folder 18)
    - Winston, Ethel, 1962 (Folder 19)
    - Wise, David, 1962 (Folder 20)
    - Woodd-Cahusac, Sydney, 1957 (Folder 21)
    - Wright, Edward L., 1960 (Folder 22)
    - Yale University Law School, 1960 (Folder 23)
    - Yeagley, J. Walter, 1958-1960 (Folder 24)
    - Miscellaneous (Folder 25)
  - Cigarette package from Shishkin, 500 ruble note (Folder 26)
  - Court proceedings for payment of fees (Folder 27)
  - Debevoise, Thomas (Folder 28)
    - CR 45094 - Search warrant issued on, 1957 June 28 (Folder 29)
    - List of items seized on the deportation warrant at the Hotel Latham, 1957 June 21 (Folder 30)
    - List of materials confiscted on from rooms 505 and 509 at 252 Fulton Street, Brooklyn, New York, 1957 June 29 and August 18 (Folder 31)
    - Notes and worksheets
      - General (Folder 32)
      - United States of America vs. Rudolf Ivanovich Abel, U.S. Court of Appeals, briefs for appellant, 1958 February (Folder 33)
    - Requirements of all search warrants (Folder 34)
  - Diary (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Disposition of fee (Folder 2)
  - Dulles, Allen W.
    - "Khrushchev's Challenge," address to the Forty-Sixth Annual Meeting of the Chamber of Commerce of the United States, Washington, D.C., 1958 April 28 (Folder 3)
    - Remarks at the meeting of the Association of the Bar of the City of New York, 1958 October 15 (Folder 4)
  - Exhibits
    - Defense (Folder 5)
    - Government (Folder 6)
  - Facts which were known to the FBI prior to, June 21 (Folder 7)
  - FBI files bill (Folder 8)
  - Groopman, Samuel F. (Folder 9)
  - Hayhanen, Reino (Eugene Nicolai Maki) (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Hayhanen's testimony, subject index to (Folder 2)
  - Hicks, Robert W. (Folder 3)
  - Makinen, Marvin William (Folder 4)
  - Memoranda re: U.S. vs. Abel, 1959-1961 (Folder 5)
  - Notes and worksheets
    - General (Folder 6-9)
    - Appeal proceedings (Folder 10)
  - O'Connor, George J., Jr. (Folder 11)
  - Powers, Francis Gary, Hearing Before the Committee on Armed Forces, U.S. Senate, 1942 March 6 (Folder 12)
  - Pre-trial materials (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Press coverage of trial (Folder 2)
  - Rare book offers (Folder 3)
  - Reports to J. B. Donovan from FFG, 1957 September 30-October 17 (Folder 4)
  - Retainers declined
    - A-J (Folder 5)
    - K-Z (Folder 6)
  - Rhodes, Roy A. (Folder 7-8)
  - Rhodes trial decision, 1958-1959 (Folder 9)
  - "Rudolf Abel Tried Before American Court," A. V. Trishkov, Sovetskoe Gosudarstvo i Pravo, No., 4, 1969 (Folder 10)
  - Searches and seizures, constitutional law (Folder 11)
  - Statement to be issued upon receiving Abel decision (Folder 12)
  - "Strategic Intelligence-Espionage-The Powers Trial," announcement of speech by J. B. Donovan at Lake Placid in the Adirondacks, 1960 August 30 (Folder 13)
  - Subpoenae (Folder 14)
  - Supreme Court delays (Folder 15)
  - Supreme Court documents (Folder 16)
  - Trial testimony, name index (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Trip to East Berlin for Powers-Abel exchange (Folder 2)
  - "The Twenty-two Trials of Mr. Abel," Richmond News Leader, 1957 August 8 (Folder 3)
  - United States District Court (New York), Rudolf I. Abel, Petitioner, United States of America, Respondent
    - Notice of motion, 1957 June 21 (Folder 4)
    - Civil No. 124-160
      - Affidavits (Folder 5)
      - Memorandum in opposition to the government's motion (Folder 6)
      - Memorandum in opposition to petitioner's motion for return of property and suppression of evidence (Folder 7)
      - Memorandum in support of the government's motion to transfer petitioner's motion to suppress (Folder 8)
      - Memorandum in support of petitioner's application (Folder 9)
      - Memorandum of law (Folder 10)
      - Request for order to return property, 1957 October 2 (Folder 11)
    - Oral argument, draft, 1958 December 17 (Folder 12)
  - United States of America vs. Rudolf I. Abel, U.S. Court of Appeals
    - Brief for appellant (Folder 13)
    - Docket No. 24968 (Folder 14)
    - Index to record on appeal (Folder 15)
    - Reply brief for appellant (Folder 16)
  - United States of America vs. Rudolf I. Abel, U.S. District Court (New York)
    - Defendant's statement (Folder 17)
    - Internal Security Authority and other statutes (Folder 18)
    - Related cases (Folder 19)
    - Sufficiency - knowledge (Folder 20)
    - Surplusage (Folder 21)
  - United States of America vs. Rudolf I. Abel, U.S. District Court (New York), Criminal No. 45094/45095, 1957 October
    - Abel, Rudolf I., sworn deposition, 1957 September (Folder 22)
    - Affidavits (Folder 23)
    - Court statement no. 45094 (Folder 24)
    - Defendant's questions for the examination of prospective jurors (Folder 25)
    - Defendant's request to charge (Folder 26)
    - Government's proposed questions to jurors on voir dire (Folder 27)
    - Government's request to charge (Folder 28)
    - Grand jury charges (Folder 29)
    - Hearing on search and seizure (Folder 30)
    - Jury list (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Lists of people who were sent material on the case (Folder 2)
    - Memorandum in opposition to defendant's motion to strike surplusage (Folder 3)
    - Memorandum in support of defendant's motion for bill of particulars (Folder 4)
    - Motion No. 2, memorandum re:, 1957 October 4 (Folder 5)
    - Notice of appeal, 1957 November 21 (Folder 6)
    - Notice of motion (Folder 7)
    - Notice pursuant to Title 18, U.S.C., Section 3432 (Folder 8)
    - Opening statement of defense counsel (Folder 9)
  - Order to show cause (Folder 10)
  - Orders (Folder 11)
  - Outline of oral argument (Folder 12)
  - Stipulation of facts (Folder 13)
    - Trial transcripts
      - Vol. 1, 1957 October 3 (Folder 14)
      - 1957 October 9 (Box 33, Folder 1)
      - 1957 October 14 (Folder 2)
      - 1957 October 21 (Folder 3)
      - 1957 October 22 (Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous (Folder 5)
  - Witnesses at trial (Folder 6)
  - Miscellaneous (Folder 7-8)
- International Military Tribunal (I.M.T.) File, 1941-1947 (Boxes 34-35)
  Record of proceedings of Eichman trial, legal plans, background materials, procedure outlines, correspondence and articles about J. B. Donovan's service as assistant to U.S. Chief Prosecutor in Nuremberg, Germany.
  - General. Printed material, 1941-1947 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Agreements by the government of the United States of America, the Provisional Government of the French Republic, the government of the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland and the government of the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics, for the prosecution and punishment of the major war criminals of the European Axis (Folder 2)
  - Alderman, Sidney S.
    - "Background and High Lights of the Nuernberg Trial,", 1946 October (Folder 3)
    - Final report of American Representative of the Four-Power Drafting subcommittee, memorandum for Chief Justice Jackson, 1945 July 11 (Folder 4)
  - Anderson, Hale, "The Nuremberg Trial,", 1947 May 26 (Folder 5)
  - Bernays, Colonel, relief from duty, 1945 August 15 (Folder 6)
  - Constitution of the International Military Tribunal (Folder 7)
  - Correspondence
    - Alderman, Sidney J., 1946 (Folder 8)
    - Bernays, Murray C., 1946 (Folder 9)
    - Donovan, William J., 1946 (Folder 10)
    - Finney, Nat, 1964 (Folder 11)
    - Fortune magazine, 1946-1947 (Folder 12)
    - Glueck, Sheld, 1946 (Folder 13)
    - Horsky, Charles, 1946 (Folder 14)
    - Jackson, Robert H., 1946-1948 (Folder 15)
    - Jackson, William, 1946-1947 (Folder 16)
    - Jordan, William, 1946 (Folder 17)
    - Kellogg, E. Ray, 1946-1947 (Folder 18)
    - Letters from students, 1958-1963 (Folder 19)
    - Letters to Mrs. Donovan (Folder 20)
    - Niles, David K., 1946 (Folder 21)
    - Pence James and Associates, 1946 (Folder 22)
    - Wallace, E. W., 1946 (Folder 23)
    - Wheeler, Leonard, 1946 (Folder 24)
  - Donovan, William J., eulogy for, by J. Donovan (Folder 25)
  - Eichmann trial, 1961-1962 (Folder 26)
  - Executive Order 9547, Providing for Representation of the United States in Preparing and Prosecuting Charges of Atrocities and War Crimes Against the Leaders of the European Axis Powers and Their Principal Agents and Accessories, 1945 May 2 (Folder 27)
  - Historical background of German aggression (Folder 28)
  - Identification cards (Folder 29)
  - Jackson, Chief Justice
    - Remarks by, n.d. (Folder 30)
    - Statement attacking Black, 1946 June 10 (Folder 31)
  - Krauch, Carl, et al., case against (Folder 32)
  - Legal problems to be encountered in the International Trial of War Criminals (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Memorandum on Trial Preparation, 1945 May 24 (Folder 2)
  - "Nazi Concentration Camps," a documentary motion picture, 1945 (Folder 3)
  - "The Nazi Plan," an official documentary motion picture, 1945 September-December (Folder 4)
  - Nizer, Louis, "The Nuremberg Verdict - An Appraisal," reprint, The American Jewish Conference, Vol. III, No., 7, 1946 October (Folder 5)
  - "The Nuernberg Trials," by James Donovan, delivered to the Federal Bar Association, 1946 October 24 (Folder 6)
  - Nuernberg reunion, 1948 November 20 (Folder 7)
  - Nuernberg Trials Official Record, pp. 1372-1648, 1945 December 13-17 (Folder 8)
  - Office of Strategic Services, War Crimes Information memoranda
    - #1, 1945 April 12 (Folder 9)
    - #2, 1945 April 30 (Folder 10)
    - #3, 1945 July 10 (Folder 11)
  - Office of Strategic Services, Research and Analysis Division
    - "Principal Nazi Organizations Involved in War Crimes,", 1945 June 5 (Folder 12)
    - "Problems Concerning the Treatment of War Criminals,", 1944 September 28 (Folder 13)
  - Plan of the war crimes trials (Folder 14)
  - Preparation of International War Crimes Prosecution (Folder 15)
  - Progress Report on Preparation of Prosecution, by James Donovan, 1945 May 30 (Folder 16)
  - Storey, Robert Gerald, "Legal Aspects of the Nuernberg Trial," speech delivered before the annual meeting of the State Bar of Texas, 1946 July 3 (Folder 17)
  - Unconditional surrender (Folder 18)
  - U.S. Army, Office of U.S. Chief of Counsel, Visual Presentation Section. Reports, 1946 February (Folder 19)
  - Wahl, Eduard, Brief on "Fundamental Questions of Law," Case VI (versus Krauch et al.) (Folder 20)
  - War Crimes Prosecutions - Planning Memorandum, 1945 May 17 (Folder 21)
  - Wheeler, Leonard, "Why the Nuremberg Trials Are Still Going On,", n.d. (Folder 22)
  - Miscellaneous (Folder 23)
- Office of Scientific Research and Development (O.S.R.D) File, 1907-1944 (Box 36)
  Contracts and memoranda relating to service as agency's counsel.
  - Appointment of alien as U.S. official, 1943 April 2 (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - Bush, Vannevar
    - "Research and the War Effort - The Development of New Weapons," an address before the American Institute of Electrical Engineers, New York City, 1943 January 26 (Folder 2)
    - "Science and National Defense,", 1941 October 24 (Folder 3)
  - Conant, James B., "University Training and War Service in Great Britain," (Folder 4)
  - Contracts (Folder 5)
  - Convention between the United States and Other Powers Respecting the Laws and Customs of War On Land, signed at The Hague, 1907 October 18 (Folder 6)
  - Correspondence
    - Beecher, Henry K., 1943 (Folder 7)
    - Carpenter, Charles M., 1943 (Folder 8)
    - Hart, Henry M., 1942 (Folder 9)
    - Potter, Dean A., 1944 (Folder 10)
    - Stewart, Irvin, 1942-1943 (Folder 11)
  - Cost-plus-a-percentage-of-cost contracts (Folder 12)
  - Council of National Defense
    - Order amending the order providing for coordination of health, welfare, and related defense activities, 1941 June 28 (Folder 13)
    - Order revoking the order creating the National Defense Research Committee, 1941 June 28 (Folder 14)
  - Executive order establishing the Office of Scientific Research and Development in the Executive Office of the President and defining its functions and duties, 1941 June 28 (Folder 15)
  - Executive orders (Folder 16)
  - Executive Secretary
    - Designation of power to, 1941 August 23 (Folder 17)
    - Powers of, 1942 July 30 (Folder 18)
  - Federal excise taxes on purchases under O.S.R.D. contracts, 1942 August 5 (Folder 19)
  - General appropriations (Folder 20)
  - Grant of revocable licenses under government-owned patents, 1924 October 28 (Folder 21)
  - Human experiments (Folder 22)
  - Insurance (Folder 23)
  - Language for Appropriation Act, 1944 (Folder 24)
  - Legal Division materials (Folder 25)
  - Legislation (Folder 26)
  - Memorandum on O.S.R.D. Operations, 1942 July 29 (Folder 27)
  - Methods of compensation of and avoidance of conflicts of interest by O.S.R.D. officials, 1943 February 17 (Folder 28)
  - National Defense Research Committee
    - Minutes of meeting, 1940 July 2 (Folder 29)
    - Order establishing, 1940 June 27 (Folder 30)
    - Press releases
      - 1940 July 2 (Folder 31)
      - 1940 October 31 (Folder 32)
  - National War Agencies Appropriation Bill, 1944 (Folder 33)
  - Negligence liability, protection from loss occasioned by, 1942 July 21 (Folder 34)
  - Office of War Information, Office of Price Adminstration (Folder 35)
  - Organization chart (Folder 36)
  - Payment by contractors of federal and state excise taxes, 1942 August 20 (Folder 37)
  - Personnel problems involved in the use of civilian analysts by the Armed Forces and suggested solution (Folder 38)
  - Poisonous gases in warfare (Folder 39)
  - Public policy and labor provisions in O.S.R.D. contracts (Folder 40)
  - Rat extermination under OEMcmr-59 (Folder 41)
  - Standardized regulations to govern the payment of living and quarters allowances to civilian officers and employees temporarily stationed in foreign countries or in the Philippine Islands, 1943 March 1 (Folder 42)
  - Statement on O.S.R.D. legislation prepared for Congressional committees, 1943 April 15 (Folder 43)
  - Transmittal of Army, Navy and O.S.R.D. material classified as secret, confidential, and restricted, 1942 February 14 (Folder 44)
  - Travelling expenses (Folder 45)
- Office of Strategic Services (O.S.S.) File, 1940-1945 (Box 37)
  Reports, memoranda, and manuals relating to legal problems handled by J. B. Donovan as general counsel, e.g. organizational legal questions, capturing prisoners, wills and insurance, problems of agents in general, authority to make certain weapons.
  - Acceptance of awards by foreign governments (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Applications for exit permits (aliens) (Folder 2)
  - Basic Directive of Board of Review (Folder 3)
  - Bills of sale (Folder 4)
  - "Bylaws of Law,", n.d. (Folder 5)
  - Censorship, Congressional investigation of (Folder 6)
  - Certifications (Folder 7)
  - Chandler, Knox, death of (Folder 8)
  - Claims for vouchered and unvouchered personnel, 1943-1945 (Folder 9-10)
  - Classification of documents (Folder 11)
  - Communists, employment of (Folder 12)
  - Complaints (Folder 13)
  - Conflict of interest (Folder 14)
  - Conscientious objectors, use of (Folder 15)
  - Contracts (Folder 16)
  - Correspondence
    - Forrestal, Secretary, 1944 (Folder 17)
    - Weir, John M., 1944 (Folder 18)
  - Destruction of records overseas (Folder 19)
  - Disclosures, forbidden and permitted, interoffice memo, 1945 September 13 (Folder 20)
  - Duty orders (Folder 21)
  - Executive orders, 1940-1943 (Folder 22)
  - Expenditures, finances, funds (Folder 23)
  - International law and war crimes (Folder 24)
  - Jurisdiction over United States Forces in foreign lands (Folder 25)
  - Leases (Folder 26)
  - Legal memoranda (Folder 27)
  - Licenses (Folder 28)
  - "Life of Hitler" (Folder 29)
  - Map Division (Folder 30)
  - Motor vehicles (Folder 31)
  - Naturalization (Folder 32)
  - O.S.S. History Project (Folder 33)
  - Office of General Counsel liaison activities (Folder 34)
  - Personnel (Folder 35)
  - Powers of attorney (Folder 36)
  - R & A Studies (Folder 37)
  - Releases (Folder 38)
  - Russian short-wave transmitter in the United States (Folder 39)
  - SI Labor Desk records in Cairo, disposition of (Folder 40)
  - Travel (Folder 41)
  - Typewriter stolen from Area "F", recovery of (Folder 42)
  - U.S. Department of State, Office of Research and Intelligence, Division of International and Funtional Intelligence, "Organizations and Individuals Authorized to Capture Prisoners of War and Booty." Report No. 2574., 1945 December 26 (Folder 43)
  - Wills (Folder 44)
  - Yovanovich, Dr. & Mrs. Peter (Folder 45)
- Cuban Prisoners Exchange File, 1962-1976 (Boxes 38-60)
  Correspondence, memoranda, Cuban trial records, lists of prisoners, requests for release, Cuban exile material, background reports, press releases, diary, secret memoranda, notes on meetings, and other material relating to the negotiation of the Cuban prisoner exchange.
  - General, 1967-1969 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    Clippings, correspondence, telegrams, and legal documents relating to the defection of Major Richard H. Pearce to Cuba. See also: OVERSIZE FILE for additional clippings.
  - American National Red Cross. Memoranda, correspondence, lists and reports relating to relief efforts for Cuban prisoners, 1962-1963 (Folder 2-12)
  - Answer by Dr. J. Donovan to the points made in the memorandum of the palace meeting of, 1962 October 10 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Arango y Cortina, Eduardo (Folder 2)
  - Articles by J. Donovan (Folder 3)
  - Betancourt, Suzette Figeroux (Folder 4)
  - Book review requests (Folder 5)
  - "Campaign Debates," WCBS-TV, program transcript, U.S. Senator J. K. Javits vs. J. B. Donovan, 1962 October 21 (Folder 6)
  - Castro, Fidel, speeches (Folder 7)
  - Chronology
    - 1962 June 20-September 10 (Folder 8)
    - 1962 September 10-October 29 (Folder 9)
    - 1962 October 29-December 29 (Folder 10)
    - 1962 January 2-1963 March 7 (Folder 11)
    - 1963 March 8-April 13 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - 1963 April 14-April 28 (Folder 2)
    - 1963 April 28-May 21 (Folder 3)
  - Chronology of the "Bay of Pigs" (Folder 4)
  - Chronology of Cuban prisoner release negotiations (Folder 5)
  - Clippings
    - General (Folder 6-8)
    - 1963
      - February-March (Folder 9)
      - April (Box 41, Folder 1-3)
      - May (Folder 4-5)
      - June (Folder 6)
  - Code (Folder 7)
  - Committees (Folder 8)
  - Correspondence
    - General. Requests relating to Cuban prisoners, 1966-1968 (Folder 9)
    - Allvyug, Bella, 1962 (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Alonso Puyol, Guillermo, 1962 (Folder 2)
    - Antell, Bert W., 1962 (Folder 3)
    - Apeland, Casper, 1963 (Folder 4)
    - Arensberg, Mariada, 1963 (Folder 5)
    - Autograph requests (Folder 6)
    - Barnett, Joseph R., 1963 (Folder 7)
    - Barreto de los Heros, Berta, 1962-1976 (Folder 8)
    - Bell, J. Raymond, 1962 (Folder 9)
    - Bessie, Mr., n.d. (Folder 10)
    - Botwin, Forence H., 1963 (Folder 11)
    - Bradford, A. Lee, 1963 (Folder 12)
    - Brigade members and their relatives, letters of thanks, 1963 (Folder 13)
    - Congratulatory letters, 1962-1964 (Folder 14-18)
    - Crackpots and critics (Folder 19)
    - Cuban Easter cards, 1965 (Folder 20)
    - Cuban Christmas cards, 1964 (Folder 21)
    - Cummings, Walter J., 1966 (Folder 22)
    - De Rosa, Frank, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Dewey, Godfrey, 1962 (Folder 2)
    - Donovan, Helen, 1962-1963 (Folder 3)
    - English, John W., 1962 (Folder 4)
    - Floberg, John F., 1962 (Folder 5)
    - Fordham University, 1965 (Folder 6)
    - German language letters (Folder 7)
    - Herd, John Victor, 1966 (Folder 8)
    - Huttlinger, Mr. & Mrs. Carl, 1962 (Folder 9)
    - Karr, Jack, 1966 (Folder 10)
    - Laufer, David, 1963 (Folder 11)
    - McWilliams, Carey, 1963 (Folder 12)
    - Manly, Chesly, 1966 (Folder 13)
    - Offers for old books (Folder 14)
    - Peterson, Anton U., 1963 (Folder 15)
    - Pinto, E. Nicholas, 1963 (Folder 16)
    - Porter, Charles O., 1963-1965 (Folder 17)
    - Red Cross, 1963 (Folder 18)
    - Requests for aid in entry to Cuba (Folder 19)
    - Robuck, Charles H., 1966 (Folder 20)
    - Rodriguez, Gilberto, 1963 (Folder 21)
    - Sanchez, Alvaro, 1975-1976 (Folder 22)
    - Scheele, Leonard, 1963 (Folder 23)
    - Students (Folder 24)
    - Telegrams of thanks and congratulations, 1962 (Folder 25-26)
    - Tetlow, Edwin, 1963 (Folder 27)
    - Viault, Albert, 1962 (Folder 28)
    - Walt, Norman E., 1962 (Folder 29)
    - Weisbrod, Burton (Folder 30)
    - Wilcox, Arthur, 1963 (Folder 31)
    - Yaguchi, Rokuzo, 1963 (Folder 32)
    - Miscellaneous (Folder 33)
  - Cuba. Ministry of Foreign Relations. "Cuba Demanded Indemnification - Imperialism Said No!" Havana, 1961 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Cuban Families Committee for Liberation of Prisoners of War
    - General (Folder 2)
    - Appointment of general counsel (Folder 3)
    - Board of Directors, minutes of meetings, 1962 December-1963 February (Folder 4)
    - Correspondence
      - Sanchez, Alvaro, Jr., 1962-1963 (Folder 5)
      - U.S. Treasury Department, Commissioner of Internal Revenue, 1962 (Folder 6)
      - Williams, Enrique Ruiz, 1962 (Folder 7)
    - Financial matters (Folder 8-9)
    - Food, medicine, products (Folder 10)
    - Fund raising
      - General (Folder 11)
      - John Price Jones Company, Inc. (Folder 12)
    - Legal standing and legal appointment of J. B. Donovan as counsel, 1962 July (Folder 13)
    - Letters of credit
      - General (Folder 14)
      - American National Red Cross (Folder 15)
    - Memorandum of agreement with Cuban government, 1962 December 21 (Folder 16)
    - Morse, Robert, memoranda (Folder 17)
    - National Sponsors Committee, 1962 August 16 (Folder 18)
    - Press clippings (Box 45, Folder 1-2)
    - Resolution adopted on, 1962 December 6 (Folder 3)
    - Ryan, John L., report on activities of CFC (Folder 4)
    - Sponsors (Folder 5)
    - "Sponsors Information Bulletin,", 1962 (Folder 6)
    - "A Statement of Purpose for the Cuban Prisoners Freedom Fund,", 1962 June 11 (Folder 7)
    - Stationery (Folder 8)
    - Supporting materials for John Price Jones Company, 1962 June (Folder 9)
  - Cuban manuscript (Folder 10-12)
  - Cuban manuscript (Box 46, Folder 1-3)
  - Del Pinto, Rafael (Folder 4)
  - Drug list (Folder 5-6)
  - "Factors Affecting the Outcome of the Bay of Pigs Prisoner Talks,", n.d. (Folder 7)
  - Film rights requests (Folder 8)
  - Firestone Tire and Rubber Company (Folder 9)
  - Garcia-Inchuastegui, Jorge (Folder 10)
  - Grau, Ramon A. (Folder 11)
  - Guevara, Ernesto Che (Folder 12)
  - Harvey, William, statement by, n.d. (Folder 13)
  - Interview requests
    - Magazine and press (Folder 14)
    - Press (Folder 15)
  - Invitations to speak
    - General (Folder 16)
    - General (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Acceptances (Folder 2)
    - Refusals (Folder 3)
    - TV interviews (Folder 4)
  - Kennedy press statement, 1962 December 12 (Folder 5)
  - Legal documents and memoranda (Folder 6)
  - Leyva-Moskowitz, Idalia (Folder 7)
  - Lopez, Mrs. Philip (Folder 8)
  - McGrath, Christopher
    - Persons admited to the US from Cuba (Folder 9)
    - Prisoner release requests (Folder 10)
    - "SS Maximus" (Folder 11)
    - Transportation requests (Folder 12)
  - Matos, Mrs. Huber and daughter Carmen (Folder 13)
  - Meeting, 1963 March 17 (Folder 14)